Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And my name is Katherine.
我叫Katherine。
And today we're talking about being on the road.
今天我们聊聊在路上遇到的情况。
Yeah, we're going to be on the road, but we're going to encounter a little bit of a car problems.
是啊，我们要上路了，但会遇到点汽车问题。
My favorite kind.
我最喜欢的那种。
Yeah.
嗯。
I think it's happened to everyone.
我觉得每个人都遇到过这种事。
You're on the road or maybe you're coming back from work, you get a flat tire or something
你在路上，或者下班回家，轮胎瘪了或者别的什么
happens to your car, right?
车出了问题，对吧？
And it's always when you're in a rush.
而且总是在你赶时间的时候。
And most of the time it's raining.
大多数时候还下着雨。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's snowing.
下着雪。
So all of the circumstances definitely, well, they don't help.
所以这些情况肯定，嗯，帮不上忙。
Let's just say.
就这么说吧。
All right.
好吧。
So before we listen to this dialogue, let's take a look at some of the words in today's
所以在听这段对话之前，我们先看看今天
vocabulary preview.
词汇预览里的几个词。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to take a look at two words.
我们要看两个词。
They're kind of strange.
它们有点奇怪。
I don't know, kind of difficult to understand.
我不知道，有点难理解。
So that's what we're going to explain them.
所以我们要解释它们。
The first one is spew, to spew.
第一个是spew，喷出。
It's a verb, okay?
这是个动词，对吧？
To spew.
喷出。
Well, what can spew?
嗯，什么能喷出？
Volcano can spew.
火山能喷出。
Exactly.
没错。
An engine can spew.
发动机能喷出。
A person can spew.
人能喷出。
Yeah.
嗯。
That's not very nice.
那不太雅观。
No.
不。
So basically it's to like expel or to shoot out from your mouth or something liquid.
所以基本上就是像从嘴里排出或喷出液体之类的东西。
So in the case of a person, right?
所以对于人来说，对吧？
So if a person spews, it means a person throws up, but it's usually very forceful.
如果一个人spew，意思是呕吐，但通常很猛烈。
All right.
好吧。
It's very messy.
很乱。
A volcano can spew lava.
火山能喷出熔岩。
Exactly.
没错。
So a volcano is spewing lava.
所以火山在喷出熔岩。
Now for the next word that we have, it's an informal way of saying that something is broken.
现在下一个词，是一种非正式的说法，表示某物坏了。
You could say it's busted.
你可以说它busted（坏了）。
It's busted.
它坏了。
My DVD player is busted.
我的DVD播放器坏了。
Man, my phone is busted.
天啊，我的手机坏了。
So it's an informal way, very popular, very common I would say, to describe that something
所以这是一种非正式的说法，很流行，很常见，用来描述某物
is not working.
不工作了。
I don't think many people actually say, well, it's broken or it's damaged.
我觉得很多人不会直接说，嗯，它坏了或受损了。
Yeah.
嗯。
They're pretty much mixed I think, but you will definitely hear busted if you're talking
它们可能混着用，但如果你和母语是英语的人说话，
to native English speakers.
你肯定会听到busted。
Or even like, for example, your arm.
或者甚至像，比如，你的胳膊。
He's got a busted arm.
他胳膊坏了。
Exactly.
没错。
So busted.
所以busted。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time.
那我们第一次听对话吧。
Let's see what's going on with this car trouble and then we'll come back and explain some
看看这个汽车问题是怎么回事，然后回来解释一些
things.
东西。
Howdy.
你好。
Nice car.
好车。
What seems to be the problem?
出了什么问题？
I don't know.
我不知道。
This stupid old car started being white smoke and it just died on me.
这辆破旧的老车开始冒白烟，然后就熄火了。
Luckily I managed to start it up and drive it here.
幸好我设法启动它开到了这里。
What do you think it is?
你觉得是什么问题？
Not sure yet.
还不确定。
How about you pop the hood and we could take a look?
你打开引擎盖，我们看看怎么样？
Mm.
嗯。
It doesn't look good.
看起来不妙。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
My daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month.
我爸爸上个月生日送我这辆车。
It's brand new.
是全新的。
Well, missy, the white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator.
嗯，小姐，你看到的白烟是散热器冒出的蒸汽。
You overheated your engine so now the pistons are busted, and so is your transmission.
你的发动机过热了，所以活塞坏了，变速箱也坏了。
You should have called us and we could have towed you over here when your car died.
你车熄火时应该给我们打电话，我们可以拖车过来。
Ugh. So, how long is this going to take? An hour?
呃。那这要多久？一个小时？
I'm afraid a bit more than that.
恐怕不止。
We need to order the spare parts, take apart your electrical system, fuel pump, and engine, and then put it back together again.
我们需要订购备件，拆开你的电气系统、燃油泵和发动机，然后再装回去。
You're going to have to leave it here for at least, uh, two weeks.
你得把车留在这里至少，呃，两周。
What? How am I supposed to go to school? Or go shopping? This is not happening.
什么？我怎么去上学？或者去购物？这不行。
So if I were the mechanic, I would not be very happy to be dealing with someone like this girl.
所以如果我是修理工，我可不会很高兴和这个女孩这样的人打交道。
I think it's, uh, well maybe it's a little bit stereotypical that we put it as a girl,
我觉得，嗯，也许有点刻板印象，我们设定成女孩，
because guys and girls, so many people don't know anything about cars or mechanics.
因为男男女女，很多人对车或机械一窍不通。
And in the States, there's a lot of female mechanics too, so it's, you know, it's mixed.
在美国也有很多女修理工，所以，你知道，是混合的。
But definitely it's something that happens all the time, and probably the mechanic will overcharge her as well,
但这绝对是经常发生的事，而且修理工可能还会多收她钱，
because apparently she doesn't know what she's doing.
因为她显然不懂。
And that's one of the reasons we want to give you the vocabulary to deal with these situations.
这也是我们想给你词汇来应对这些情况的原因之一。
So let's look at some of those car words in today's Language Takeaway.
那我们看看今天语言要点里的一些汽车词汇。
Alright, so we're going to take a look at very specific words related to cars and the engines and everything.
好的，我们要看一些和汽车、发动机等相关的非常具体的词。
So let's start with the first one.
我们从第一个开始。
Radiator.
散热器。
Radiator. Alright, so the radiator of the car.
散热器。好的，汽车的散热器。
So a radiator is something that you normally find in the front of the car near the engine.
散热器通常位于车头靠近发动机的地方。
It usually gets very, very hot, right?
它通常变得非常非常热，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
So one of the big issues is radiators getting too hot because there's no way to cool them down.
所以一个大问题就是散热器过热，因为没法冷却。
Mm-hmm. So if you live in a place that's very hot, the radiator keeps your engine cool because it has water in it.
嗯。如果你住在很热的地方，散热器通过里面的水保持发动机冷却。
So if it overheats, or maybe you didn't put enough water in there, then it'll start spewing steam like in this dialogue.
所以如果它过热，或者你没加够水，它就会像对话里那样开始冒蒸汽。
And if you have a problem with your radiator, you could actually do a lot of damage to your engine, which is why this is important.
如果散热器有问题，你可能会对发动机造成很大损害，所以这很重要。
Exactly, and that's what happened in this dialogue.
没错，对话里就是这样。
So a radiator. Now, because the radiator wasn't working well, it overheated the engine, and he said they had some busted pistons.
所以散热器。现在，因为散热器工作不好，发动机过热了，他说活塞坏了。
So broken pistons. Pistons are important because they're kind of like valves that go up and down.
所以活塞坏了。活塞很重要，因为它们有点像上下运动的阀门。
Right. So inside your engine, you have mini explosions, and the pistons move up and down, and that's what actually moves your car.
对。所以在你的发动机内部，有微型爆炸，活塞上下运动，这就是驱动汽车的动力。
Right. And so pistons, in general, are things in mechanics. So like a trumpet has pistons, things that go up and down and that allow for the flow of air.
对。所以活塞，一般来说，是机械中的部件。就像小号有活塞，上下运动，让空气流通。
Air or something like that. Very good. So that's a piston. And, well, another very common mechanic term is the transmission.
空气之类的。很好。那就是活塞。嗯，另一个很常见的机械术语是变速箱。
Alright, so the transmission. What happens if your transmission dies? Can you still drive?
好的，变速箱。如果你的变速箱坏了，会发生什么？你还能开车吗？
You basically can't move, or maybe you only have one gear or two gears.
你基本上动不了，或者可能只有一档或两档。
Alright, so think about transmission as coming from the word to transmit. That means to transfer.
好的，把变速箱想象成来自“传输”这个词。意思是转移。
So this is the part of the car that transfers energy or the power to actually move the car. So the transmission.
所以这是汽车的一部分，负责传递能量或动力来驱动汽车。这就是变速箱。
And we've got the mechanic who says, well, we've got to order you some spare parts. So first, let's look at the word spare.
然后我们听到修理工说，嗯，我们得给你订一些备件。所以首先，我们来看看“备件”这个词。
What's another word for spare? Additional, maybe extra.
“备件”的另一个词是什么？额外的，也许是多余的。
Right. So spare means extra. Parts are, well, pieces. So he's talking about ordering a new transmission, new pistons, things to replace the broken things.
对。所以“备件”意思是多余的。“零件”嘛，就是部件。所以他是在说订一个新的变速箱、新的活塞，用来替换坏掉的东西。
Spare parts. So this is where you go to the mechanic to get some spare parts and get them installed.
备件。这就是你去修理工那里拿备件并安装它们的情况。
You probably don't have many spare parts at home, right? You got a transmission lying around.
你家里可能没有很多备件，对吧？你不可能有个变速箱随便放着。
Well, yeah, so spare parts. And the last word that we're going to take a look at is a fuel pump.
嗯，是的，备件。我们要看的最后一个词是燃油泵。
Okay, so a pump is, you could have a bike pump.
好的，泵，你可以有自行车打气筒。
A water pump.
水泵。
Water pump. So these are something, these are some things that we use very, very often.
水泵。所以这些是我们非常非常常用的东西。
But a fuel pump is something that allows gas, gasoline, to get into your engine.
但燃油泵是一种让汽油进入发动机的装置。
So it's basically a device that pushes gasoline into the engine so you can start.
所以它基本上是一个把汽油推入发动机以便启动的装置。
And that's the same thing with the water pump. It's a device that pushes water.
水泵也是一样的道理。它是一个推水的装置。
Or an air pump is something that pushes air into your tires and your bicycle.
或者气泵是把空气推入轮胎和自行车轮胎的装置。
Exactly. So a fuel pump, water pump, etc.
没错。所以燃油泵、水泵等等。
Wow, I feel like we know a lot about cars.
哇，我觉得我们对车了解很多了。
Yeah, apparently we do. See? Alright, so now that we've taken a look at all of these great words, let's move on to a couple of phrases in Fluency Builder.
是啊，看来我们确实懂。看到了吧？好了，既然我们已经看了所有这些好词，让我们继续看流畅表达中的几个短语。
Alright, these are phrases that you hear sometimes when you're talking about electronics.
好的，这些是你在谈论电子产品时有时会听到的短语。
But in today's lesson, we're also talking about specific car phrases.
但在今天的课程中，我们也在谈论特定的汽车短语。
So you're going to hear these all the time at the mechanics.
所以你在修车厂会经常听到这些。
Right, and the first one is, the car suddenly died on me.
对，第一个是，车突然在我面前熄火了。
Alright, to die on. So we keep these two words together, die on.
好的，“die on”。我们把这两个词放在一起，“die on”。
Oh man, so while you were driving, your car died. It stopped moving.
哦天哪，所以当你开车时，你的车熄火了。它停止移动了。
So that means that it doesn't work anymore.
所以那意味着它不再工作了。
And it's not only for cars, right? You can say my MP3 player died on me today.
而且这不只适用于车，对吧？你可以说我的MP3播放器今天在我面前坏了。
Exactly, and what it means is, it's not like you left it and you forgot about it and you tried it again and it didn't work.
没错，它的意思是，不是你把它放着忘了，然后又试了一次发现它不工作了。
It means while you're using it, it dies. It doesn't work.
而是你在使用它的时候，它坏了。它不工作了。
So I think this phrase is a good one to give some other examples. So let's listen.
所以我觉得这个短语是个好例子，可以举一些其他例子。让我们听听。
So this next one is a phrase you hear, the first thing you hear maybe, when you tell someone you have a car problem.
所以下一个是你可能会听到的短语，也许是你告诉别人你有车问题时听到的第一句话。
Right, you tell them to pop the hood.
对，你让他们打开引擎盖。
Or let's pop the hood. So this means let's open the front part of the car, the hood, to look at the engine, transmission, all those parts.
或者“让我们打开引擎盖”。所以这意味着打开汽车的前部，引擎盖，看看发动机、变速箱和所有那些部件。
Exactly. So you can say open the hood, but the most common one is pop the hood.
没错。所以你可以说“打开引擎盖”，但最常用的是“pop the hood”。
So the reason is because there is a little spring and you have to pull inside the car and it goes pop, and there's a little jump.
原因是里面有一个小弹簧，你得在车里拉一下，它会“砰”一声弹开，然后跳起来一点。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
So it's literally popping.
所以它真的是弹开的。
Right, or you can also say the trunk, right, the back part of the car.
对，或者你也可以说后备箱，对吧，车的后部。
Hey, can you pop the trunk for me? I've got to put some stuff inside.
嘿，你能帮我打开后备箱吗？我得放些东西进去。
Exactly, so pop the hood, pop the trunk.
没错，所以“pop the hood”，“pop the trunk”。
And next we've got this girl actually, who's talking about her car because she just got this car.
接下来我们有一个女孩，她在谈论她的车，因为她刚买了这辆车。
So what's another way to say it's a new car?
那么说它是新车还有什么别的说法？
It's brand new.
它是全新的。
Is that more new than new?
那比“新”还要新吗？
It's like newer, newer than new.
它更新，比新还新。
Alright, so brand, you think about brands like Ford or Gucci, these are brands, but brand new means she maybe got it like today.
好的，所以“brand”，你会想到品牌比如福特或古驰，这些是品牌，但“brand new”意味着她可能今天才拿到车。
So it's brand new, it's very, very new.
所以它是全新的，非常非常新。
Did you see my brand new watch?
你看到我全新的手表了吗？
Oh, it is nice, did you get it? Alright, so brand new.
哦，真好看，你买了吗？好的，全新的。
And well, the last phrase that we have for you today is to take apart something.
嗯，我们今天给你的最后一个短语是“拆开某物”。
Alright, so this is very popular with young children, like they like to take things apart so they can find out how they work.
好的，这在小孩中很常见，比如他们喜欢拆东西，以便弄清楚它们是怎么工作的。
But to take apart means to take all the pieces and to pull them out.
但“拆开”意思是把所有零件都取出来。
Yeah, I used to do that a lot when I was a kid.
是啊，我小时候经常这么做。
I used to take apart any electronic device to kind of see how it works and then I would try to put it back together again.
我过去常常拆开任何电子设备，想看看它是怎么工作的，然后我会试着再把它装回去。
That's why you're so smart.
这就是你为什么这么聪明。
Well, it never really worked, it worked half the time.
嗯，其实从来没真正成功过，一半时间能行。
So the problem is always putting them back together again, right?
所以问题总是把它们再装回去，对吧？
Exactly, so you can take it apart, but then you put it back together and there's always a screw missing or a screw that's extra or two or three parts.
没错，所以你可以拆开它，但然后你把它装回去，总是会多一个螺丝或少一个螺丝，或者多两三个零件。
Not a good sign.
不是好兆头。
Alright, so we've taken a look at a lot of great words and phrases, so let's listen to this dialogue for the last time.
好的，我们已经看了很多好词和短语，所以让我们最后听一遍这段对话。
Not sure yet. How about you pop the hood and we can take a look?
还不确定。你打开引擎盖，我们看看怎么样？
Mmm, doesn't look good.
嗯，看起来不妙。
What do you mean? My daddy gave me this car for my birthday last month. It's brand new.
你什么意思？我爸爸上个月生日送我这辆车。它是全新的。
Well, missy, the white smoke that you saw is steam from the radiator.
嗯，小姐，你看到的白烟是散热器冒出的蒸汽。
You overheated your engine so now the pistons are busted and so is your transmission.
你让发动机过热了，所以现在活塞坏了，变速箱也坏了。
You should have called us and we could have towed you over here when your car died.
你当时应该给我们打电话，我们可以在你车熄火时把它拖过来。
Ugh, so how long is this going to take? An hour?
呃，那这要多久？一个小时？
I'm afraid a bit more than that. We need to order the spare parts, take apart your electrical system, fuel pump and engine, and then put it back together again.
恐怕不止。我们需要订备件，拆开你的电气系统、燃油泵和发动机，然后再装回去。
You're going to have to leave it here for at least two weeks.
你得把车留在这里至少两周。
What? How am I supposed to go to school? Or go shopping? This is not happening.
什么？那我怎么去上学？或者去购物？这不行。
Alright, so car trouble. Have you ever had any very serious car trouble or something weird happened to your car?
好的，车的问题。你有没有遇到过非常严重的车问题，或者你的车发生过什么奇怪的事？
Actually, the week before I decided to leave Chicago, I had this 1991 Honda Civic hatchback, so only two doors.
实际上，在我决定离开芝加哥的前一周，我有一辆1991年的本田思域掀背车，只有两扇门。
And I was driving home from work, I was on the highway, had the radio on, the windows open, and then doo doo doo doo, boom.
我下班开车回家，在高速公路上，开着收音机，窗户开着，然后嘟嘟嘟嘟，砰。
It died.
它熄火了。
It died in the middle of the highway during rush hour. So that's when there's tons of cars and I didn't know what to do.
它在高峰时段的高速公路中间熄火了。就是车很多的时候，我不知道该怎么办。
So I'm calling people and then all of a sudden I see someone tapping on my window. And there's cars everywhere.
所以我正在打电话，突然看到有人在敲我的窗户。到处都是车。
And it's this guy. And he's like, listen, do you need a hand? I said yes.
是个男的。他说，听着，你需要帮忙吗？我说是的。
So I put the car in neutral so that there's no brake. And he pushed it to a side road and gave me a ride home.
所以我把车挂到空挡，这样就没有刹车了。他把它推到一条小路上，然后载我回家。
No way.
不会吧。
He was the coolest guy, he was so nice. And he was just there with his truck, he's a gardener, and just gave me a ride home.
他是最酷的人，他太好了。他当时就开着他的卡车，他是个园丁，然后载我回家了。
It was super, super cool.
超级超级酷。
Wow.
哇。
And so it turns out my engine died. No, the engine was new, it was the transmission, it was shot. It was totally broken.
结果是我的发动机坏了。不，发动机是新的，是变速箱坏了。它完全坏了。
Wow.
哇。
But I was very lucky to have such a kind person.
但我很幸运遇到这么好的人。
Yeah, that's a good story because usually people are too afraid or maybe a little bit reluctant to stop and see if you're okay or if you need a ride or something.
是啊，这是个好故事，因为通常人们太害怕，或者可能有点不愿意停下来看看你是否还好，或者是否需要搭车之类的。
Because you can't really trust people these days.
因为现在的人不太可信。
But it's good. Once I saw somebody on the side of the road that had a flat tire, it was two girls and they didn't know what to do.
但这是好事。有一次我看到有人在路边爆胎了，是两个女孩，她们不知道该怎么办。
So I was passing by. It was actually raining. And I was like, hey, do you guys need a hand?
所以我正好路过。当时还在下雨。我说，嘿，你们需要帮忙吗？
And they're like, yeah, please. We can't locate my dad or whatever. So I was like, changing the tire, it's not a big deal, right?
她们说，是的，拜托。我们联系不上我爸爸之类的。所以我说，换轮胎，没什么大不了的，对吧？
And they wanted to tip me, they wanted to give me some money.
她们想给我小费，想给我一些钱。
Are you serious?
你认真的吗？
They're like, oh, please take this, you're so kind, your time, and you're all wet. And I'm like, no, no, don't worry about it.
她们说，哦，请收下这个，你太好了，你的时间，而且你全身都湿了。我说，不，不，别担心。
That's a nice thing to do. If you know anything about cars, I mean, or if you can offer someone a lift.
那是件好事。如果你懂点车的话，我是说，或者如果你能载别人一程。
I know it's not terribly safe to ride with strangers, but this guy totally helped me out.
我知道和陌生人一起坐车不太安全，但这个人完全帮了我。
Nice. All right. Well, maybe you guys have some cool or maybe some interesting stories of what's happened with your cars or maybe you've helped somebody out.
不错。好了。嗯，也许你们有一些关于你们的车发生的酷事或有趣的故事，或者也许你帮助过别人。
So come to our website at EnglishPod.com and let us know.
所以来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们吧。
And of course, if you have any questions about the vocabulary or phrases that you heard today, please ask away.
当然，如果你对今天听到的词汇或短语有任何问题，请尽管问。
Don't hesitate. And, well, again, we hope to see you on the website.
别犹豫。嗯，再次希望能在网站上见到你。
All right. We'll see you guys there.
好的。我们那里见。
Bye.
再见。
EnglishPod 1998.
EnglishPod 1998。